Eric Wahlgren-Sauro

Software Engineer

Summary

After almost two years as a software engineer, I have developed a strong foundation around what makes for quality code. I appreciate the collaborative process that goes into determining what is worth building just as much as I enjoy creating software.

Employment

Crownpeak

Software Engineer

Denver, CO Oct. 2017 to Apr. 2019

- Served on engineering team of ~15 that builds and maintains a content management system
- Became highly proficient at quickly navigating a large code-base on both the front and back end
- · Developed in two-week sprint cycles
- · Led bi-weekly lessons on various programming topics to my team
- Used daily: Angular, AngularJS, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Green Mountain Semiconductor

Burlington, VT Jan. 2016 to May 2016

Mar. 2018 to Apr. 2019

Business Development Intern

- Generated leads for potential partners and/or customers that may wish to utilize the latest DRAM technology being developed
- · Researched markets for the company's cutting-edge IP
- Worked side-by-side the engineering team, learning about in-memory architecture and chip design processes

Projects

Sapien | beta.sapien.network

- Sapien is a JavaScript based web application that improves upon the core functionality of Reddit
- · Team of four developers
- · Platform utilizes the Ethereum Blockchain
- Contributed key features, prior to the public release while the platform was in private beta

Commute Tracker | commute--tracker.herokuapp.com

- Commute Tracker is a **Ruby on Rails** web application that allows users to track an approximate commute time for a year between two points
- Solo project
- Google Directions API for calculating traffic, rendering a Google iFrame for displaying the map directions
- Google OAuth for user authentication
- · Deployed using Heroku

Volunteering

Denver Urban Scholars (DUS) · Mentor Denver, CO

- · Served as a mentor for a STRIVE prep high school student
- Spent time with my mentee bi-weekly, teaching him to climb
- · Attended community DUS events

Contact/Info

- **∠** cwahlgrensauro@gmail.com
- cews7.github.io
- **** 303-842-0167
- Openver, CO
- in charleswahlgrensauro
- cews7

Skills

LANGUAGES

TypeScript/JavaScript HTML/CSS Ruby

FRAMEWORKS

Angular AngularJS Ruby on Rails

TOOLS/OTHER

Git

Less

RSpec

Education

Turing School of Software & Design

Certificate in Web Applications
Development with Ruby, Ruby on Rails,
and JavaScript

Champlain College
BS International Business